A Guide to the Papers of J. Warren White, Jr. 1970-1979
Special Collections, Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
The Papers of J. Warren White, Jr. 1970-1979
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
MG 24
36 Document Cases, 15 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of J. Warren White, Jr. December, 1978.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joshua Warren White, Jr., was born in Norfolk, Virginia on August 27, 1916. Of Scottish and Swiss descent, White is the son of Joshua Warren White, M.D., and Emily Johnston White. White graduated from Maury High School in Norfolk in 1935 and attended Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia for three years. After leaving college, White was called to duty by the United States Navy and was given a commission as an Ensign. He served for four and a half years during World War II and was discharged as a Lieutenant Commander. On August 31, 1940, he married Dorothy Lee Winstead of Norfolk with whom he had four children.
White was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates in 1961 where he served for 18 years. He was Chairman of the Privileges and Elections Committee and also served on the Appropriations, Rules, Chesapeake and Its Tributaries, and Interstate Cooperation Committees. Several of the major pieces of legislation that White introduced became law. Among them are the complete reorganization of the Virginia Milk Commission, creation of The Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, which led to the formation of The Eastern Virginia Medical School, and legislation that provided $5,333 per student per year (1974) in state funds for all students attending the School. He also sponsored legislation appropriating $450,000 in 1976 to be used for Family Practice at Eastern Virginia Medical School. During the 1978 session of the legislature, he was largely responsible for having $4.5 million per biennium appropriated for indigent care costs to all hospitals in Tidewater that were teaching institutions for the Medical School. Also, he sponsored legislation that created a state scholarship fund for students attending private institutions of higher learning in Virginia.
In addition to his service as a Virginia Delegate, White led an active business, civic and social life. In business, White served as President and Treasurer of the Old Dominion Paper Company. He was a member of the Board of Directors of Norfolk State University; the Medical Center Hospitals; the United Community Fund; Virginia National Bank, Norfolk Board; and the Edgewater-Turney Home for Boys and Girls. White also served on the Board of Trustees of Mary Baldwin College; the Tidewater Development Council; and the Jamestown Foundation. He was President (1946) of the Young Democratic Clubs of Virginia, and a member of the Second District Democratic Committee and the State Central Democratic Committee. White attended the First Presbyterian Church in Norfolk where he was a member of the Board of Deacons. He was also a member of the Princess Anne Country Club, Norfolk Yacht & Country Club, Norfolk German Club and the Commonwealth Club of Richmond, Virginia.
White died at the age of 69 in November, 1985.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of J. Warren White are primarily legislative correspondence, records, and reference material from his service in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1971-1979. The collection contains correspondence between White, his constituents and other Virginia legislators. The files reveal information concerning his position and vote on many controversial issues of the 1970s. Of special interest are the folders concerning his stand on the Equal Rights Amendment, the Sunday Closing Laws, and Pari-mutuel Gambling. In addition to various books and magazines, the collection contains reports and studies of Committees in the Virginia Senate and House of Delegates.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The Legislative Files (Series I and III) are arranged in alphabetical order by folder title. The Legislative Reference Material (Series II) is arranged in alphabetical order by book, document, or pamphlet title.
Organization
The papers are divided into three series. Series I is entitled Legislative Files 1974-1976, it includes legislative business papers, copies of legislation and correspondence with constituents. Series II is entitled Legislative Reference Material 1971-1977, it includes publications and reports of various organizations and government agencies. Series III is material added to the collection after the first two series were organized. It contains material similar to that in Series I and includes the period from 1971-1979 with the bulk of the papers being from 1977-1979.
Contents List
- Legislative Files 1974-1976
  - Abortion (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Absentee Voting (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bill Status Printout (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Blue Laws (I), 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Blue Laws (II), 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blue Laws (III), 1974 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bond Issue (I), 1977 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bond Issue (II), 1977 (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Charitable Immunity (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Child Abuse (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Coleman Lobbying Bill (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 11)
  - College Peer Grouping (Box-folder Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Department of Corrections (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Doctors-Family Care (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dusinberre-Lot Line (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical School, 1970-1971 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical School, 1971-1972 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical School, 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical School, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (I) 1973 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (II) 1974 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (III) 1974 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (IV) 1974 (Box-folder Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (V) 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (VI) 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (VII) 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (VIII) 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (IX) 1974 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (X) 1975 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Equal Rights Amendment, (XI) 1976 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Favors (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 8)
  - General Assembly Session, (Summary) 1970 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 9)
  - General Assembly Session, 1972 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Assembly Session, 1972 (Box-folder Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (I), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence (II), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence (III), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence (IV), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence (V), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence (VI), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence (VII), 1974 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Hemophilia (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Henderson Correspondence-ERA, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Higher Education (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Highways (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Hollow-Point Ammunition (Box-folder Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Horse Racing in Virginia-Petitions Against (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 1)
  - House Appropriations Committee, 1974 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 2)
  - House Appropriations Committee, 1975 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 3)
  - House Appropriations Committee, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Housing (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Institute of Marine Science (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Invitations-1976 Session (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Invitations, Acceptances, 1976 (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Juvenile Court Relations (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Land Use and Environmental Protection (Box-folder Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Legislation, 1973 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Legislation-Bills, 1973 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Legislation, 1974 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Legislation, 1975 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Legislation, 1976 (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Malpractice (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Malpractice Legislation in Other States (I) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Malpractice Legislation in Other States (II) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Mary Baldwin College (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Marine Resources Commission (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Medical Schools (I) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Medical Schools (II) (Box-folder Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mental Health (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Mentally Retarded (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mileage Bill (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Milk Commission (Report of the Commission), 1974 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Milk Commission, January-October, 1974 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Milk Commission, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Bills (Support/Oppose) (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous One-Time Correspondence 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous One-Time Correspondence 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings (I), 1973 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings (II), 1973 (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Norfolk, City of (Box-folder Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Norfolk Public Schools (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Norfolk Savings and Loan, 1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Nursing, 1970-1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Old Dominion University (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pari-Mutuel Gambling, 1974 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pari-Mutuel Gambling, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pendleton Project (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Precinct Workers (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Privileges and Elections (I), 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Privileges and Elections (II), 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Privileges and Elections (III), 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Privileges and Elections (IV), 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Privileges and Elections (V), 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Proposals for 1972 Session (Box-folder Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Public Collective Bargaining, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Public Collective Bargaining, 1975 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Public Collective Bargaining, 1976 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Public Hearings, 1974-1976 (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Registered Lobbyists, 1975-1976 Session (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Retired Military-Tax Exemptions (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Senate and House Finance Committees, (I) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Senate and House Finance Committees, (II) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Senior Citizens-Hospitalization and Medical Needs (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Single Member Districts (I) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Single Member Districts (II) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Single Member Districts (III) (Box-folder Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (I), 1974-1976 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (II), 1974-1976 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (III), 1974-1976 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 3)
  - State Corporation Commission (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 4)
  - State Retirement Programs-Report 1973 (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Vehicular System-Tidewater (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Commission on Interstate Cooperation (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Virginia State Crime Commission (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Virginia Port Authority (Box-folder Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Wage Differential, 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Wage Differential, 1974 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Wage Differential, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Virginia Wage Differential-Document (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Watchmaker's Licensing (Box-folder Box 11, Folder 5)
- Legislative Reference Material, 1971-1977
  - ABCs of School Finance (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol Drug Abuse: Interim Report to the Virginia General Assembly, January 19, 1976 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 2)
  - American Legislative Exchange Council: Suggested State Legislation, 1977 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report: Commissioner of the Revenue, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report: Department of Taxation, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report: Superintendent for Public Instruction, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report: Virginia Alcohol Safety Action Program-Highway Safety Division, 1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report: The Virginia State Board of Nursing, 1974 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts (Commonwealth of Virginia) Report on Comparative Cost of County Government, 1973 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Bikeway Development Study, 1973 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Brewer, Dr. Carey: Remarks on Finance, 1976 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Budget Advisory Committee (2 Folders) 1975 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 12)
  - California Office of Consumer Counsel (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Capital Outlay Recommendations, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Chiropractors: Healers or Quacks? (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Code of Virginia, 1950 (Box-folder Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Collective Bargaining and Virginia Public Schools: Perspectives and Implications, 1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Commission to Study the Rights of Public Employees (Report), 1973 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Commission on State Governmental Management (Sixteen Interim Report), 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth: The Magazine of Virginia- February, 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Board of Nursing-Rules and Regulations (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: 1973 Session Amendments to the Budget, 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Department of Corrections, 1976 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Department of Law-Report, 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Final Report of the Electricity Cost Commission, 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: State Registration Board for Contractors-Report, 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Office on Aging-Technical Report, 1976 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Commonwealth of Virginia: Official Election Results for 1973 in the General Election, November 6, 1973 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Compact (Magazine), Summer, 1976 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Consumer Complaints in the South, 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Consumer Math: Selected Results from the First National Assessment of Mathematics, 1975 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Council of State Governments: Suggested State Legislation, 1976 (Box-folder Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Crime in Virginia, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Data for the House Appropriations Committee, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Death without Dignity: Killing for Mercy, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Department of Corrections: Institutional Programs, 1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Department of Corrections and Department of Welfare-Staff Report, 1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Department of Taxation, Statements and Reports, 1973-1974 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Digest of Acts of Assembly, 1976 Session (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Directory of Virginia's Post-secondary Education and Training Opportunities, 1976-1977 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Division of Consumer Counsel-Report, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Draft Legislation to Implement Commission Recommendations (Commission on State Governmental Management), 1976 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The Drug Control Act-Amended, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Effect of Senate Amendments on Higher Education (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Equal Rights Monitor, 1976 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Ethyl Digest, Special Bicentennial Edition, 1976 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Family Planning Services: Focus for State Initiative, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Federal Register, November 26, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Final Cumulative Index of Bills, Resolutions, Joint Resolutions, and Documents for the Commonwealth of Virginia General Assembly, Volume I, 1975 (Box-folder Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Final Cumulative Index of Bills, Resolutions, Joint Resolutions, and Documents for the Commonwealth of Virginia General Assembly, Volume II, 1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Financial Assistance to attend Virginia Colleges and Universities, 1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Financing Virginia's Colleges, 1972-1974 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Fiscal Prospects and Alternatives, 1976 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Five-Year Plan: Standards of Quality in Norfolk Public Schools, 1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 5)
  - The Future of the South, 1974 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 6)
  - General Assembly-Acts of Amendment and Reenactment (2 copies), 1975 (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 7)
  - General Reference (Box-folder Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Groundwater, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Growing Needs, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Guarding our Water Resources, 1974 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Guide to Land Management, 1974 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Higher Education in Virginia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Highway Safety Division of Virginia, Annual Report, 1975-1976 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 6)
  - House Appropriations Committee: Amendments to RB 30, 1976 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 7)
  - House Appropriations Committee: Review of Selected Capital Outlay Planning Projects, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 8)
  - House Appropriations Committee: Staff Report on the Department of Highways and Transportation, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 9)
  - House Appropriations Committee: Staff Report on Law Enforcement, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 10)
  - House Appropriations Committee: Staff Report on Sum Sufficient Appropriations, 1975 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 11)
  - House Bill No. 30: Public Revenue, 1974 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 12)
  - House Bill No. 30: Public Revenue, 1976 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 13)
  - House Document No. 1: The Budget Bill, 1974 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 14)
  - House Document No. 3: 1975 Report of the Virginia Housing Study Commission, 1976 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 15)
  - House Document No. 4: Status of Women, 1976 (Box-folder Box 16, Folder 16)
  - House Document No. 5: A Study of the Feasibility of a Special Graduated Farm Truck Use License for Virginia, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 1)
  - House Document No. 6: Family Planning Services, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 2)
  - House Document No. 7: Report of Telecommunication in the Field of Special Education, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 3)
  - House Document No. 8: A Study of Contrasting Practices of Planning District Commissions, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 4)
  - House Document No. 9: Abuse of Temporary License Procedures for Life Insurance Agents, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 5)
  - House Document No. 10: Report Regarding the Establishment of an Instructional Television Fixed Service System in the Williamsburg/Hampton Area, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 6)
  - House Document No. 11: Report of the Department of Welfare, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 7)
  - House Document No. 12: Report of the Dulles International Airport Development Commission, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 8)
  - House Document No. 13: Report of the Virginia State Crime Commission on Law Enforcement Liability Insurance, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 9)
  - House Document No. 17: Study of Local Government Interim Report of the Virginia Advisory Legislative Council, 1977 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Improved Health Care for Virginians, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Injuries to Railroad Employees: Article 6 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 12)
  - It's the Call that Counts: No one Answer to Teenage Decisions about Alcohol (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 13)
  - James River Comprehensive Water Quality Management Study, May, 1973 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Jamestown and the Republic: An Address by Colgate W. Darden, Jr. July 30, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission: Virginia Drug Abuse Control Programs, 1975 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission: Working Capital Funds in Virginia, 1976 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Journal of Law and Education, October, 1973 (Box-folder Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Legislation Program, 1975 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Legislation Program, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Legislation Digest, 1975 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Legislation Digest, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Legislation Leaders, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Legislative Tax Guide (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Liaison Officers between State Agencies and the General Assembly and Its Staff (2 copies), 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Local Financial Concerns, Vols. I and II, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Local Tax Rates, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Mailing Lists (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Management of Virginia State Government: A Report for Public Discussion, 1975 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Manual of Correctional Facilities and Services-Department of Corrections (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Medical Center Hospitals-Financial Statements, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Medical College of Virginia Hospitals Facilities Development Programs, 1976 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Medical Malpractice Insurance in Virginia: The Scope and Severity of the Problem and Alternative Solutions, 1975 (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Reference (Box-folder Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Municipal Policy Statement, 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Names of Persons Registering to vote from April 1, 1972 (under 21 years of age) (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Narcotic and Dangerous Drug Squad, 1971 Report (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 3)
  - National Conference of State Legislatures (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Official Election Results-General Election and Special Elections, 1975, 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 5)
  - The Paper Bag Institute, Inc.-General Meetings (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Pendelton Project: Semi-Annual Report, 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Potomac Conference: Toward a Potomac Action Strategy-The Pre-Conference Report, 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Privacy, 1974 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Proposed Equity and Equalification Measures Impact on Selected Localities, 1976 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Public Sector Labor Relations, 1975 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Public Service Commissions in the South, and the Role of People's Counsels, 1975 (Box-folder Box 19, Folder 12)